

TAMEEM UZ ZAMAN

Software Developer Computer Science Graduate

ABOUT ME

I hold a Computer Science degree from University of Technology Malaysia and worked as a Software Developer at Wavelet Solutions. My prior expertise in Software Development feeds my enthusiasm to continue my career as an esteemed Software Engineer.

CONTACT



+8801978761755 (Whatsapp)



tameemturag@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/tameem-turag-507791147



github.com/Tameem786

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE (COMPUTER NETWORKS & SECURITY)

University of Technology Malaysia CGPA: 3.70/4.00 (Dean's Award)

HIGHER SECONDARY CERTIFICATE

2015-2017

2019-2023

Notre Dame College, Dhaka

GPA: 5.00/5.00

SECONDARY SCHOOL CERTIFICATE

2005-2015

Rajshahi Collegiate School, Rajshahi

GPA: 5.00/5.00

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

May 2023 - Nov 2023

Wavelet Solutions Sdn Bdn Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Developed Web Applications using Springboot.
- Used Angular, NgRx for Front-end developing.
- Used Jira for issue ticketing.
- Use JUnit Test to test Java backend codes

SECURITY ANALYST INTERN Oct 2022 - Feb 2023

Firmus Sdn Bhd, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Network Penetration testing using Nmap tool.
- Web application Penetration testing using Nessus and burp suit.
- Mobile Penetration testing using adb tool.
- Writing detailed reports on vulnerability assessment.

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Aug 2020 - Jan 2022

Al Research Lab, UTM, Johor, Malaysia

- Worked under Dr. Madni's supervision.
- Taught juniors C++, Python, R Programming.
- Assisted other students in developing their projects.
- Used PyTorch to build neural networks with the help of optimized algorithms.
- Explored muscle simulation software using Virtual Reality.

ACHIEVEMENTS

ACADEMIC

DEAN'S AWARD

I was honored with the prestigious Dean's Award for achieving an outstanding CGPA of 3.70, surpassing the required threshold of 3.67.

DEAN'S LIST AWARDS

- Dean's List Award (2018/2019-2)
- Dean's List Award (2019/2020-1)
- Dean's List Award (2019/2020-2)
- Dean's List Award (2020/2021-2)
- Dean's List Award (2022/2023-1)

COURSE CERTIFICATIONS

- Become a Spring Boot Developer
- Full-Stack Development with Spring Boot and Vue.js

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

IMDC MALAYSIA 2022 (RUNNER'S UP)

Got shortlisted for my final year project where I used Arduino and nodeMCU to build an energy monitoring system.

NASA SPACE APP CHALLENGE 2019 (RUNNER'S UP)

Our team was chosen for our innovative game development idea aimed at helping students learn about planets.

ORGANIZATIONS

CYBERX CLUB, UTM

- Worked as a Technical Writer
- Organized weekly workshops
- Participated in hackathons

TOASTMASTER CLUB, UTM

- · Worked as a Treasurer
- Planned the budgets for events

PROJECTS

Ecommerce Application

An Ecommerce website using Angular, Typescript for Front-End and NodeJS for Backend.

Skills - Node.js · MongoDB · Postman API · Stripe · AngularJS

Ecommerce-Backend

Develop backend server using NodeJS.

Skills - REST APIs · Node.js · MongoDB · Postman API

Food-Chain Web Development

This website is build to provide food supply among students. Backend (PHP Laravel Framework with MySQL database)

Skills - Laravel \cdot MySQL \cdot PHP

Spring-Boot-Reactive

A application for describing the difference between spring MVC and webFlux.

Skills - Reactive Programming · Spring Webflux · REST APIs · Java · Spring Boot

UTM - Industrial Training System

This is a Mobile Application which help students to find their internships. This project is built with Flutter and Firebase database.

Skills - Flutter · Dart · Firebase

IOT BASED SMART ENERGY MONITORING SYSTEM (FINAL YEAR PROJECT)

Worked on developing an IoT based smart energy monitoring system which helped tracking electric bills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Object Oriented Programming Kafka Hibernate Data Structure & Algorithms MySQL Angular PostGreSQL CI/CD React Linux **AWS** Jira Laravel C++ Javascript Java Spring Security Agile Springboot MongoDB Postman HTTP